William Allan Neilson Personal Papers, 1852-1946 RG 32.02.personal
Smith College Archives
- Series I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, 1852-1982; 8 linear feet
  - Writings About Neilson
    - "Neilson of Smith" by Marjorie Hope Nicolson: typescript and earlier versions, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 232)
    - Neilson of Smith by Margaret Farrand Thorp: correspondence (A-Z), 1946-1957 (Box 11, Folder 233-49)
    - Neilson of Smith by Margaret Farrand Thorp: reviews, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 250)
    - Neilson of Smith by Margaret Farrand Thorp: typescript (Box 11)
      [See Box 12]
    - "President Neilson of Smith" by Elizabeth Cutter Morrow, Atlantic Monthly, 1946 November (Box 11, Folder 251)
    - "President Neilson of Smith College" by John S. Tatlook, The Nation, 1928 January 4 (Box 11, Folder 252)
    - "Successful Educators, William Allan Neilson," American Education, 1925 June (Box 11, Folder 253)
    - "William Allan Neilson" by Cynthia Walsh (Ivy Day Oration), Hampshire Bookshop, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 254)
    - William Allan Neilson: Blueprint for Biography, various authors, Hampshire Bookshop, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 255)
    - "William Allan Neilson: Liberal Educator," Focus, 1939 March (Box 11, Folder 256)
    - "Word Study: William Allan Neilson," by Margaret Farrand Thorp, undated (Box 11, Folder 256a)
    - Neilson of Smith by Margaret Farrand Thorp: typescript, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
  - Oversize
    - Medals
      - Harvard, 1906 (Box 13)
      - Wyon, London, undated (Box 13)
      - Spain, 1930 (Box 13)
      - Cigar Case, undated (Box 13)
      - Harvard Advocate, 1866? (Box 13)
      - Angus Club, Edinburgh, 1885-1886 (Box 13)
      - Harvard Lampoon, undated (Box 13)
      - University of Paris, undated (Box 13)
      - Montrose Academy Dux, English Department, 1885-1886 (Box 13)
    - University of Edinburgh class notes, 1886-1891 (Box 14)
  - Family
    - Muser: diary of Elisabeth Muser Neilson's grandmother, 1888-1891 (Box 15)
    - Margarete Muser: story, "Zu Weinachten", 1900 (Box 15)
    - Margarete Muser: journal excerpts in Elisabeth Muser's handwriting(2 volumes), undated (Box 15)
    - Lina Muser: diary, 1939-1944 (Box 15)
    - Oskar Muser: war experiences, 1870-1871 (Box 15)
    - Oskar Muper: news clippings, undated (Box 15)
    - David Neilson: diary, 1884 (Box 15)
    - Oskar Muser: "Lebeaserinerungen", undated (Box 15)
  - Writings About Neilson - Volumes
    - William Allan Neilson: Blueprint for Biography (Northampton: Hampshire Bookshop, 1947) (Box 15)
    - Herring, Hubert, Neilson of Smith (Brattleboro: Stephen Daye Press, 1939) (Box 15)
    - Thorp, Margaret Farrand, Neilson of Smith (New York: Oxford University Press, 1956) (Box 15)
  - Family - Volumes
    - Neilson, Elisabeth Muser, The House I Knew (Boston: Houghton Mifflin Co., 1941) (Box 15)
  - General - Volumes, Miscellaneous
    - Burns, Robert. The Ring and the Book, Vol. II and III (from WAN library) (Box 15)
    - Scott, Sir Walter, Bacon's Essays (from WAN library) (Box 15)
    - The Inauguration of President Neilson (Northampton: Smith College, 1917) (Box 15)
- Series II. PHOTOGRAPHS AND PORTRAITS, 1883-1948; 1 linear feet
  Photographs consists primarily of black and white photographs of William Allan Neilson. There are also photographs of Neilson's family, Elisabeth Muser Neilson and her family, and of Scotland. There is a small amount of correspondence with photographers and a 19th-century Neilson family photograph album.
  Portraits consists of photographic reproductions of oil, charcoal, and silhouette portraits plus correspondence about the portraits arranged by the name of the artist.
  - Photographs
    - List of oversize photographs (Box 16, Folder 257)
    - Photographers: correspondence, miscellaneous, 1932-1939 (Box 16, Folder 258)
    - William Allan Neilson, 1883-1945 (Box 16, Folder 259-84)
    - Parents and siblings, 1892-1899; undated (Box 16, Folder 285)
    - Children and grandchildren, 1920-1944; undated (Box 16, Folder 286)
    - Elisabeth Muser Neilson, 1906; 1939; undated (Box 16, Folder 287)
    - Muser family, 1906-1933 (Box 16, Folder 288)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939; undated (Box 16, Folder 289)
    - Scotland, countryside, undated (Box 17, Folder 290)
    - Scotland, Doune and Montrose, 1891; undated (Box 17, Folder 291)
  - Portraits
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 292)
    - Folisbee, John, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 293)
    - Goodnow, C.S., undated (Box 17, Folder 294)
    - Hopkinson, Charles Sidney, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 295)
    - James, Alexander P., 1939 (Box 17, Folder 296)
    - Watson, Elizabeth V. Taylor, undated (Box 17, Folder 297)
    - Silhouette: Alfred Vance Churchill, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 298)
    - Sketches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 17, Folder 299)
    - Photograph album: Neilson relatives, unidentified, undated (Box 17, Folder 299)
    - Photograph panorama: dedication of Burns statue, Detroit, 1921 July 23 (Box 17, Folder 299)
- Series III. ACADEMIC LIFE, 1898-1941; 3.5 linear feet
  This series consists of correspondence, lecture notes, news clippings, and press releases pertaining to Neilson's life as a college professor and administrator. The material is arranged by the name of the institution. Oversize material is in a separate sequence.
  - Bryn Mawr College: miscellaneous, 1898-1901 (Box 18, Folder 300)
  - Columbia University: miscellaneous, 1904-1906 (Box 18, Folder 301)
  - Sorbonne: correspondence, 1914-1915 (Box 18, Folder 302)
  - Sorbonne: lecture notes, 1914 December (Box 18, Folder 303)
  - Harvard University and Radcliffe College
    - Miscellaneous, 1901-1904; 1906-1917 (Box 18, Folder 304)
    - Clubs: correspondence, membership certificates, 1911-1916 (Box 18, Folder 305)
    - Correspondence
      - A-D, 1901-1904; 1906-1917 (Box 18, Folder 306)
      - Dodd, Isabel F., 1902; undated (Box 18, Folder 307)
      - E-K, 1901-1904; 1906-1917 (Box 18, Folder 308)
      - Fabyan, George, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 309)
      - Fyock, Alice, 1900 (Box 18, Folder 310)
      - Jennings Alice, 1902-1903 (Box 18, Folder 311)
      - Kittredge, George Lyman, 1906-1916 (Box 18, Folder 312)
      - L-P, 1901-1904; 1906-1917 (Box 18, Folder 313)
      - Lowell, A. Lawrence, 1914-1915 (Box 18, Folder 314)
      - R-Z, 1901-1904; 1906-1917 (Box 18, Folder 315)
      - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1902-1917 (Box 18, Folder 316)
    - Miscellaneous, 1901-1917; undated (Box 18, Folder 317)
    - Lecture notes, English 8, 1900-1901 (Box 18, Folder 318-23)
    - Lecture notes, English 8, 1904 (Box 18, Folder 324-25)
    - Lecture notes, English 8a, undated (Box 18, Folder 326)
    - Lecture notes, English 8b, undated (Box 18, Folder 327)
    - Lecture notes, English 11, 1902 (Box 19, Folder 328)
    - Lecture notes, English 24, 1916-1917? (Box 19, Folder 329)
    - Lecture notes, English 28, 1912 (Box 19, Folder 330)
    - Lecture notes, English 28, undated (Box 19, Folder 331)
    - Lecture notes, English 32, undated (Box 19, Folder 332-3)
    - Lecture notes, English 32, 1901-1902 (Box 19, Folder 324-39)
    - Lecture notes, English 40, undated (Box 19, Folder 340-43)
    - Lecture notes, English 41, undated (Box 19, Folder 344)
    - Lecture notes, English 42, undated (Box 19, Folder 345)
    - Lecture notes, English 49, 1906 (Box 19, Folder 346)
  - Smith College
    - Miscellaneous: press releases, writings, bookplates, 1917-1939 (Box 20, Folder 347)
    - Anniversary (10th): correspondence, 1927 (Box 20, Folder 348)
    - Anniversary (10th): news clippings, 1927 (Box 20, Folder 349)
    - Anniversary (20th): miscellaneous, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 350)
    - Anniversary (20th): news clippings, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 351)
    - Appointment: congratulatory correspondence, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 352-61)
    - Appointment: general correspondence, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 362-63)
    - Birthday celebrations, 1924-1939 (Box 20, Folder 364)
    - Chronology (Box 20, Folder 365)
    - Inauguration
      - Address by Charles W. Eliot, 1918 June 13 (Box 20, Folder 366)
      - Address by WAN, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 367)
      - Booklet, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 368)
      - Correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box 20, Folder 369)
      - Guest list, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 370)
      - Invitations and program, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 371)
      - News clippings, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 372)
      - Plans, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 373)
    - Lecture notes, English 19, 1920-1926 (Box 21, Folder 374-5)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1917-1941 (Box 21, Folder 376)
    - Retirement
      - Correspondence A-Z, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 377-81)
      - "A Dictionary of Appreciation of WAN", 1939 (Box 21, Folder 382)
      - Tributes by Foreign Policy Association members, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 383)
      - News clippings, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 384)
      - Tributes, miscellaneous, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 385)
  - Oversize
    - Columbia University: Class Roll Book, 1905-1906 (Box 22)
    - Smith College: retirement gift - silver box, 1939 (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous notes on books, undated (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Shakespeare, undated (Box 22, Folder 386)
- Series IV. OTHER ACTIVITIES, 1891-1946; 4.5 linear feet
  This series documents Neilson's professional and volunteer activities outside of his primary employment. The series has two sections: 'Organizations' and 'Subjects'. Unless otherwise noted the folders contain only correspondence.
  The first section, 'Organizations,' is arranged alphabetically by the name of the organization.
  Material has been filed in the second section, 'Subjects,' where Neilson was involved with a number of organizations or causes with a similar focus.
  - Organizations
    - A, 1921-1934 (Box 23, Folder 387)
    - Affiliated Schools for Workers, 1925-1935 (Box 23, Folder 388)
    - American Arbitration Crusade, 1925-1928 (Box 23, Folder 389)
    - American Association for Old Age Security, 1929-1931 (Box 23, Folder 390)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1922-1939 (Box 23, Folder 391)
    - American Civil Liberties Union: case of Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, 1933-1941 (Box 23, Folder 392)
      [See also Box 33]
    - American Civil Liberties Union: Committee on Academic Freedom, 1932-1941 (Box 23, Folder 393)
    - American Civil Liberties Union: correspondence, 1939-1941 (Box 23, Folder 394)
    - American Civil Liberties Union: "National Defense", 1939-1941 (Box 23, Folder 395)
    - American Civil Liberties Union: "Labor", 1941 (Box 23, Folder 396)
    - American Committee to Protect the Foreign Born, 1939-1940 (Box 23, Folder 397)
    - American Defenders of Freedom, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 398)
    - American Dialect Society, 1921-1934 (Box 23, Folder 399)
    - The American Foundation, 1929-1931 (Box 23, Folder 400)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1921-1931 (Box 23, Folder 401)
    - American Otological Society, 1931-1939 (Box 23, Folder 402)
    - Amherst Memorial Fellowship Committee, 1921-1937 (Box 23, Folder 403)
    - Amherst Regional Planning Board, 1928-1932 (Box 23, Folder 404)
    - B, 1903-1938 (Box 23, Folder 405)
    - Bacon Archaeological Research, 1927-1932 (Box 23, Folder 406)
    - Beaver County Day School, 1935-1938 (Box 23, Folder 407)
    - Bennington College, 1922-1938; undated (Box 23, Folder 408-11)
    - Brearly School, 1924-1935 (Box 23, Folder 412)
    - James Bryce Fellowship, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 413)
    - C, 1920-1941 (Box 23, Folder 414)
    - Carnegie Foundation, 1928-1939 (Box 23, Folder 415)
    - Committee of 100 on Ireland, 1920-1921 (Box 23, Folder 416)
    - Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin America, 1928-1939 (Box 23, Folder 417)
    - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 418)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1921-1939 (Box 23, Folder 419)
    - Cummington School (Playhouse-in-the-Hills), 1919-1935 (Box 23, Folder 420)
    - D, 1933-1937 (Box 24, Folder 421)
    - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1928 (Box 24, Folder 422)
    - Deerfield Academy, 1932-1935 (Box 24, Folder 423)
    - Democratic Party, 1920-1940 (Box 24, Folder 424)
    - Denison House, 1924-1933 (Box 24, Folder 425)
    - E, 1923-1939 (Box 24, Folder 426)
    - English Speaking Union of the United States, 1920-1939 (Box 24, Folder 427)
    - F, 1925-1940 (Box 24, Folder 428)
    - Facsimile Text Society, 1934-1935 (Box 24, Folder 429)
    - Folger Shakespeare Memorial Fund, 1934 (Box 24, Folder 430)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1921-1939 (Box 24, Folder 431-33)
    - G, 1921-1936; undated (Box 24, Folder 434)
    - H, 1929-1939 (Box 24, Folder 435)
    - Harvard Liberal Club, 1918 (Box 24, Folder 436)
    - Harvard University, 1915-1944; undated (Box 24, Folder 437-39)
    - Harvard University, Committee on Dormitory Requirements and Relations of the Graduate Schools, 1922-1931 (Box 24, Folder 440)
    - Harvard University, Committee to Visit the English Department, 1920-1934 (Box 24, Folder 441-43)
    - Hebrew University, 1925-1939 (Box 24, Folder 444)
    - Highlander Folk School, 1934-1939 (Box 24, Folder 445)
    - Hofstra College, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 446)
    - Human Welfare Group, 1929-1931 (Box 24, Folder 447)
    - I, 1922-1939; undated (Box 24, Folder 448)
    - International Free Trade League, 1918-1920 (Box 24, Folder 449)
    - International Study Center for Democratic Reconstruction, 1943? (Box 24, Folder 450)
    - International YMCA College, 1924-1935 (Box 24, Folder 451)
    - J, 1924-1939; undated (Box 24, Folder 452)
    - K, 1920-1933 (Box 24, Folder 453)
    - Kraus Defense Committee, 1934-1936 (Box 24, Folder 454)
    - L, 1920-1939 undated (Box 24, Folder 455)
    - League of Women Voters, 1922-1939 (Box 24, Folder 456)
    - Life Extension Institute, 1920-1922 (Box 24, Folder 457)
    - M, 1921-1939; undated (Box 25, Folder 458)
    - Massachusetts Civic League, 1929-1938 (Box 25, Folder 459)
    - Massachusetts Conference of Social Work, 1917-1934 (Box 25, Folder 460)
    - Massachusetts Council for the Abolition of the Death Penalty, 1927-1930 (Box 25, Folder 461)
    - Medieval Academy of America, 1940; undated (Box 25, Folder 462)
    - Milwaukee-Downer College, 1921-1936 (Box 25, Folder 463)
    - Modern Language Association, 1918-1939 (Box 25, Folder 464-65)
    - Modern Language Association, Permanent Fund, 1916-1924 (Box 25, Folder 466-67)
    - N, 1920-1939 (Box 25, Folder 468)
    - National Committee for Independent Courts, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 469)
    - National Committee of the U.S. to Restore the Louvain Library, 1922-1930 (Box 25, Folder 470-72)
    - National Economic League, 1921-1930 (Box 25, Folder 473)
    - National Recovery Administration, 1931-1935 (Box 25, Folder 474)
    - National Research Council, 1919-1928 (Box 25, Folder 475-76)
    - New England Medical Center, 1929-1930 (Box 25, Folder 477)
    - New School for Social Research, 1918-1942; undated (Box 25, Folder 478-81)
    - O, 1923-1939 (Box 25, Folder 482)
    - The Open Road, 1926-1944 (Box 25, Folder 483-85)
    - P-Q, 1925-1940 (Box 26, Folder 486)
    - Plymouth Tercentenary Committee, 1920 (Box 26, Folder 487)
    - Poetry Society of America, undated (Box 26, Folder 488)
    - R, 1920-1940 (Box 26, Folder 489)
    - Roosevelt Memorial Association, 1934-1936 (Box 26, Folder 490)
    - S, 1918-1936 (Box 26, Folder 491)
    - School of Parents' Education, Jerusalem, 1925-1935 (Box 26, Folder 492)
    - Shady Hill Country Day School, 1934 (Box 26, Folder 493)
    - Society for Ethical Culture, 1922-1938 (Box 26, Folder 494)
    - T-U, 1921-1929 (Box 26, Folder 495)
    - Thomas Davidson Society, 1917-1932 (Box 26, Folder 496)
    - Trustees of Public Reservations, 1925-1933 (Box 26, Folder 497)
    - U, 1891-1946 (Box 26, Folder 498)
    - W-Z, 1921-1939 (Box 26, Folder 499)
    - Western Massachusetts Regional Planning Association, 1931-1937 (Box 26, Folder 500)
    - Williams College, 1921-1936 (Box 26, Folder 501)
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1921-1922 (Box 26, Folder 502)
    - Worcester Academy, 1925-1926 (Box 26, Folder 503)
  - Subjects
    - Adult Education
      - Miscellaneous, 1928-1938; undated (Box 27, Folder 504)
      - American Association for Adult Education, 1927-1939 (Box 27, Folder 505-09)
      - Committee on University Extension in the Connecticut Valley, 1917-1939 (Box 27, Folder 510)
      - Eliot Foundation for Adult Education, 1933-1938 (Box 27, Folder 511)
      - Holyoke Workers' Classes, 1928; 1938 (Box 27, Folder 512)
      - National University Extension Association, 1918-1935 (Box 27, Folder 513)
      - Springfield Adult Education Forum, 1934-1939 (Box 27, Folder 514)
    - Albania, 1924-1939 (Box 27, Folder 515)
    - Armenia, 1921-1925 (Box 27, Folder 516)
    - Asia, 1928-1938 (Box 27, Folder 517)
    - Birth Control, 1928-1942 (Box 27, Folder 518)
    - Children: miscellaneous, 1925-1940 (Box 27, Folder 519)
    - Children: Child Study Association, 1928-1938 (Box 27, Folder 520)
    - Children: Child Welfare League, 1934 (Box 27, Folder 521)
    - Children: Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, 1921-1946 (Box 27, Folder 522)
    - China, 1938-1940 (Box 27, Folder 523)
    - Clubs
      - Miscellaneous, 1920-1939; undated (Box 27, Folder 524)
      - Burns Club, 1919-1937 (Box 27, Folder 525)
      - Harvard Clubs, 1918-1928 (Box 27, Folder 526)
      - Tavern Club, 1921-1936 (Box 27, Folder 527)
      - Town Hall Club, 1932-1939 (Box 27, Folder 528)
    - Consumer: miscellaneous, 1918; 1939 (Box 27, Folder 529)
    - Consumer: Consumer's-League of Massachusetts, 1924-1932 (Box 27, Folder 530)
    - Consumer: National Consumers' League, 1922-1938 (Box 27, Folder 531-32)
    - Coolidge, 1920-1929 (Box 27, Folder 533)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1919-1939 (Box 27, Folder 534)
    - Democracy: correspondence and news clippings, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 535)
    - Educational
      - Miscellaneous, 1918-1937 (Box 27, Folder 536)
      - Moro Educational Foundation, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 537)
      - National Council of Teachers of English, 1922-1930 (Box 27, Folder 538)
      - New England Association of Teachers of English, 1922-1930 (Box 27, Folder 539)
      - Progressive Education Association, 1925-1939 (Box 27, Folder 540)
    - Eugenics, 1920-1930 (Box 27, Folder 541)
    - Germany: miscellaneous, 1924-1939; undated (Box 28, Folder 542)
    - Germany: Carl Schurz Memorial Foundation, 1932-1936 (Box 28, Folder 543)
    - Industrial, 1921-1932 (Box 28, Folder 544)
    - International Cooperation, 1926-1939 (Box 28, Folder 545)
    - Italy, 1928-1934 (Box 28, Folder 546)
    - Labor: miscellaneous, 1925-1939 (Box 28, Folder 547)
    - Labor: Community Labor Board, 1918-1919 (Box 28, Folder 548-50)
    - League of Nations
      - Miscellaneous: correspondence, news clippings, 1918-1940; undated (Box 28, Folder 551)
      - League of Free Nations, 1918-1930 (Box 28, Folder 552)
      - League of Nations Association, 1920-1938 (Box 28, Folder 553)
      - League of Nations Non-Partisan Association, 1921-1935 (Box 28, Folder 554)
      - Model League of Nations Assembly, 1928-1936 (Box 28, Folder 555)
      - Pro-League Independents, 1920-1922 (Box 28, Folder 556)
    - Mental Hygiene
      - Massachusetts Society for Mental Hygiene, 1919-1939 (Box 28, Folder 557)
      - National Committee for Mental Hygiene, 1920-1935 (Box 28, Folder 558)
    - Militarism in Education, 1925-1937 (Box 28, Folder 559)
    - Miscellaneous, unidentified, 1920-1939; undated (Box 28, Folder 560)
    - Near East, 1923-1936; undated (Box 28, Folder 561)
    - Northampton
      - Miscellaneous, 1919-1939 (Box 28, Folder 562)
      - Academy of Music, 1917-1938 (Box 28, Folder 563-564)
      - Better Housing Campaign, 1934-1935 (Box 28, Folder 565)
      - Chamber of Commerce, 1920-1939 (Box 28, Folder 566)
      - Cooley Dickinson Hospital, 1917-1926 (Box 28, Folder 567)
      - Northampton Hotel Company, 1922-1936 (Box 28, Folder 568)
      - People's Institute, 1914-1939 (Box 28, Folder 569-70)
    - Peace
      - Miscellaneous, 1919-1942; undated (Box 29, Folder 571)
      - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1928-1939 (Box 29, Folder 572)
      - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 573-83)
      - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1941-1945 (Box 30, Folder 584)
      - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace: news clippings and miscellaneous, 1939-1945 (Box 30, Folder 585)
      - National Committee on the Cause & Cure of War, 1930-1940 (Box 30, Folder 586)
      - National Council for the Prevention of War, 1931-1934 (Box 30, Folder 587)
      - Women's International League for Peace & Freedom, 1922-1935 (Box 30, Folder 588)
    - Periodicals
      - Miscellaneous, 1920-1940 (Box 30, Folder 589)
      - Atlantic Monthly, 1924-1939 (Box 30, Folder 590)
      - Collier's Weekly, 1916-1919 (Box 30, Folder 591)
      - The Delineator, 1921-1933 (Box 30, Folder 592)
      - The Forum, 1924-1939 (Box 30, Folder 593)
      - The Nation, 1919-1938 (Box 30, Folder 594)
      - The New Republic, 1921-1925 (Box 30, Folder 595)
      - New York, miscellaneous, 1920-1939; undated (Box 30, Folder 596)
      - Saturday Review, 1925-1936 (Box 30, Folder 597)
    - Political Activities
      - Miscellaneous; correspondence, news clippings, 1913-1940; undated (Box 30, Folder 598)
      - Fascism, Nazism, 1933-1940 (Box 30, Folder 599)
      - Sacco and Vanzetti case, 1924-1936; undated (Box 30, Folder 600-01)
    - Public Affairs, 1935-1939 (Box 30, Folder 602)
    - Publishers
      - Miscellaneous A-Z, 1919-1939 (Box 30, Folder 603-04)
      - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1922-1928 (Box 30, Folder 605)
      - P. F. Collier & Son, 1916-1944 (Box 30, Folder 606-15)
      - Dictionary of American Biography, 1927-1928 (Box 30, Folder 616)
      - Doubleday, 1927-1938 (Box 30, Folder 617)
      - Harbor Press, 1929-1939 (Box 30, Folder 618)
      - Harcourt, Brace & Company, 1920-1939 (Box 30, Folder 619)
      - Houghton, Mifflin Company, 1904-1930 (Box 30, Folder 620)
      - Alfred A Knopf, Inc., 1925-1938 (Box 30, Folder 621)
      - G.C. Merriam & Company: correspondence, 1937-1940 (Box 31, Folder 622-24)
      - G.C. Merriam & Company, Synonymy: "Antonyms", undated (Box 31, Folder 625)
      - G.C. Merriam & Company, Synonymy: "The Historical Development…", undated (Box 31, Folder 626)
      - G.C. Merriam & Company, Synonymy: "The Treatment of Synonyms and Antonyms", undated (Box 31, Folder 627)
      - G.C. Merriam & Company, Synonymy: carbons, pp. 66-219, undated (Box 31, Folder 628-30)
      - G.C. Merriam & Company, Synonymy: minutes, 1937-45 (Box 31, Folder 631-35)
      - W.W. Norton Company, 1929-1939 (Box 31, Folder 636)
      - Scott, Foresman & Company, 1909-1931 (Box 31, Folder 637)
      - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1925-1939 (Box 31, Folder 638)
      - Stanford University Press, 1935-1938 (Box 31, Folder 639)
      - Viking Press, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 640)
    - Race Relations
      - Miscellaneous, 1930-1931 (Box 31, Folder 641)
      - Committee of 100 Dedicated to the Creation of an America of Justice and Equality for Our Negro Fellow Citizens, 1944-1945 (Box 31, Folder 642)
      - Harmon Awards for Distinguished Achievement among Negroes, 1928-1931 (Box 31, Folder 643)
      - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1922-1944 (Box 31, Folder 644)
    - Refugee
      - Miscellaneous: correspondence, news clippings, 1920-1945; undated (Box 31, Folder 645)
      - National Institute of Immigrant Welfare, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 646)
      - National Refugee Service, 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 647)
    - Religious
      - Miscellaneous, 1925-1939; undated (Box 31, Folder 648)
      - National Conference of Jews and Christians, 1931-1939 (Box 31, Folder 649)
    - Russia
      - Miscellaneous, 1926-1937; undated (Box 32, Folder 650)